up.edu 2019-06-14

# Privacy Statement | University of Portland

## Official Web Disclaimer

Information in the University of Portland website(s) is provided by many different people. While we try to keep the site accurate and up-to-date, we cannot guarantee that it always will be. If you find content that should be corrected or updated, please contact the appropriate office, department, or the webmaster at [webmaster@up.edu](mailto:webmaster@up.edu). Please be sure to provide the full URL or website address in your message.

Unless otherwise noted, the UP website(s) may not represent official statements or views of University of Portland. 

## Americans with Disabilities Act

This publication will be made available in accessible formats upon request. Please contact [webmaster@up.edu](mailto:webmaster@up.edu) or call 503.943.7000 for further information.

## Privacy Statement

UP is committed to respecting internet users’ privacy and recognizing the need for appropriate protection and management of the personally identifiable information shared at the site. The following statement addresses the information-gathering and dissemination practices for the UP website.

### Personal Information

UP does not collect personal information (e.g., name, address or telephone number) unless you voluntarily provide it by sending email, participating in a survey or completing an online form. We do not share any personal information with any third parties.

When you visit the UP website, we collect certain information such as:

  * Domain, country, IP address
  * Browser, platform, resolution
  * Entrance-exit pages, referrals
  * Date, time
  * Search terms and search engines

The collected information allows UP to make the site more useful to visitors, better manage resources, and investigate security concerns.

In order to provide better and more secure service, we may use a “cookie”. A cookie is a small piece of information stored on your computer that can uniquely identify your browser, and may include other information about your visit to the site. The cookie cannot be read by a website other than the site that created the cookie.

### Security

University of Portland is dedicated to preventing unauthorized data access, maintaining data accuracy, and ensuring the appropriate use of information. UP strives to put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial safeguards to secure the information collected online. However, site visitors supply personal data at their own risk.

### Links to External Sites

The University of Portland website contains links to other sites which may request personal information. In such instances, the privacy policy applicable to that site will govern the collection and use of personal information. UP is not responsible for the collection and distribution of personal information that is collected on these sites.

### Google Analytics

University of Portland uses Google Analytics, a website traffic tracking and reporting service. This service helps the university to better understand and improve the visitor’s experience and site performance. 

## Questions

Should site visitors have questions or concerns about this privacy statement, please contact Curt Pederson, chief information officer, at [pedersoc@up.edu](mailto:pedersoc@up.edu), 503.943.8000, or at 5000 N Willamette Blvd, University of Portland, Portland, OR 97203.
